<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Alexander</string>
    <string name="first">First</string>
    <string name="second">Second</string>
    <string name="third">Third</string>
    <string name="fifth">Fifth</string>
    <string name="fourth">Fourth</string>
    <string name="alex_location">
        Alexandria is a port city located on the Mediterranean Sea in northern Egypt founded in 331 BCE by Alexander the Great.\n
        It is most famous in antiquity as the site of the Pharos,
        the great lighthouse, considered one of the seven wonders of the ancient world,
        for the Temple of Serapis, the Serapion, which was part of the legendary library at Alexandria, as a seat of learning and, once,
        the largest and most prosperous city in the world.\n
        It also became infamous for the religious strife which resulted in the martyrdom of the philosopher Hypatia of Alexandria in 415 CE.\n
        The city grew from a small port town to become the grandest and most important metropolis in ancient Egypt.</string>
    <string name="climate">
        Alexandria has a borderline hot desert climate approaching a hot semi-arid climate (BSh).\n
        As the rest of Egypt\'s northern coast, the prevailing north wind, blowing across the Mediterranean,
        gives the city a less severe climate from the desert hinterland.\nRafah and Alexandria are the wettest places in Egypt
        the other wettest places are Rosetta, Baltim, Kafr el-Dawwar, and Mersa Matruh.\n The city\'s climate is influenced by
        the Mediterranean Sea, moderating its temperatures, causing variable rainy winters and moderately hot summers that,
        at times, can be very humid; January and February are the coolest months, with daily maximum temperatures typically ranging
        from\n 12 to 18 °C (54 to 64 °F) and minimum temperatures that could reach 5 °C (41 °F).\n Alexandria experiences violent storms,
        rain and sometimes snow, sleet and hail during the cooler months; these events, combined with a poor drainage system,
        have been responsible for occasional flooding in the city. \nJuly and August are the hottest and driest months of the year,
        with an average daily maximum temperature of 30 °C (86 °F). \nThe average annual rainfall is around 200 mm (7.9 in)
        but has been as high as 417 mm (16.4 in)
        Port Said, Kosseir, Baltim, Damietta and Alexandria have the least temperature variation in Egypt.\n
        The highest recorded temperature was 45 °C (113 °F) on May 30, 1961,
        and the coldest recorded temperature was 0 °C (32 °F) on January 31, 1994.
</string>
    <string name="alexander_the_great">
        Alexandria is believed to have been founded by Alexander the Great in April 332 BC as  (Alexandria).\n
        Alexander\'s chief architect for the project was Dinocrates.\n
        Alexandria was intended to supersede Naucratis as a Hellenistic center in Egypt, and to be the link between Greece and
        the rich Nile valley.\n Although it has long been believed only a small village there, recent radiocarbon dating of seashell
        fragments and lead contamination show significant human activity at the location for two millennia preceding Alexandria\'s founding
        Alexandria was the intellectual and cultural center of the ancient world for some time.\n
        The city and its museum attracted many of the greatest scholars, including Greeks, Jews and Syrians.\n
        The city was later plundered and lost its significance.\n
        In the early Christian Church, the city was the center of the Patriarchate of Alexandria,
        which was one of the major centers of early Christianity in the Eastern Roman Empire.\n
        In the modern world, the Coptic Orthodox Church and the Greek Orthodox Church of Alexandria both lay claim to this ancient heritage.\n
        Just east of Alexandria (where Abu Qir Bay is now), there was in ancient times marshland and several islands.\n As early as the 7th century BC,
        there existed important port cities of Canopus and Heracleion.\n The latter was recently rediscovered under water.\n
        An Egyptian city, Rhakotis, already existed on the shore and later gave its name to Alexandria in the Egyptian language.\n
        It continued to exist as the Egyptian quarter of the city.\n A few months after the foundation,
        Alexander left Egypt and never returned to his city.\n After Alexander\'s departure, his viceroy, Cleomenes, continued the expansion.\n
        Following a struggle with the other successors of Alexander,
        his general Ptolemy Lagides succeeded in bringing Alexander\'s body to Alexandria,
        though it was eventually lost after being separated from its burial site there.
    </string>
    <string name="Muhammads_era">
        The Islamic prophet Muhammad\'s first interaction with the people of Egypt occurred in 628,
        during the Expedition of Zaid ibn Haritha (Hisma).\n He sent Hatib bin Abi Baltaeh with a letter to the king of Egypt
        (in reality Emperor Heraclius) and Alexandria called Muqawqis In the letter Muhammad said: "I invite you to accept Islam,
        Allah the sublime, shall reward you doubly. \nBut if you refuse to do so,
        you will bear the burden of the transgression of all the Copts".\n
        During this expedition one of Muhammad\'s envoys Dihyah bin Khalifa Kalbi was attacked, Muhammad sent Zayd ibn Haritha to help him.\n
        Dihya approached the Banu Dubayb (a tribe which converted to Islam and had good relations with Muslims) for help.\n
        When the news reached Muhammad, he immediately dispatched Zayd ibn Haritha with 500 men to battle.\n
        The Muslim army fought with Banu Judham, killed several of them (inflicting heavy casualties), including their chief,
        Al-Hunayd ibn Arid and his son, and captured 1000 camels, 5000 of their cattle and 100 women and boys.\n
        The new chief of the Banu Judham who had embraced Islam appealed to Muhammad to release his fellow tribesmen,
        and Muhammad released them.
    </string>
    <string name="ibn_battuta">
        In reference to Alexandria, Egypt, Ibn Battuta speaks of great saints that resided here.\n
        One of them being Imam Borhan Oddin El Aaraj.\n He was said to have the power of working miracles.\n
        He told Ibn Battuta that he should go find his three brothers, Farid Oddin, who lived in India,
        Rokn Oddin Ibn Zakarya, who lived in Sindia, and Borhan Oddin, who lived in China.\n
        Battuta then made it his purpose to find these people and give them his compliments.\n
        Sheikh Yakut was another great man.\nHe was the disciple of Sheikh Abu Abbas El Mursi,
        who was the disciple of Abu El Hasan El Shadali, who is known to be a servant of God.\n
        Abu Abbas was the author of the Hizb El Bahr and was famous for piety and miracles.\n
        Abu Abd Allah El Murshidi was a great interpreting saint that lived secluded in the Minyat of Ibn Murshed.\n
        He lived alone but was visited daily by emirs, viziers, and crowds that wished to eat with him.\n
        The Sultan of Egypt (El Malik El Nasir) visited him, as well.\n Ibn Battuta left Alexandria with the intent of visiting him.
    </string>
    <string name="temple_of_tapo">
        The temple was built in the Ptolemy era and dedicated to Osiris, which finished the construction of Alexandria.\n
        It is located in Abusir, the western suburb of Alexandria in Borg el Arab city.\n
        Only the outer wall and the pylons remain from the temple.\n
        There is evidence to prove that sacred animals were worshiped there.\n
        Archaeologists found an animal necropolis near the temple.\n
        Remains of a Christian church show that the temple was used as a church in later centuries.\n
        Also found in the same area are remains of public baths built by the emperor Justinian, a seawall, quays and a bridge.\n
        Near the beach side of the area, there are the remains of a tower built by Ptolemy II Philadelphus.\n
        The tower was an exact scale replica of the destroyed Alexandrine Pharos Lighthouse.
    </string>
    <string name="library_of_alex">
        The Royal Library of Alexandria or Ancient Library of Alexandria in Alexandria, Egypt,
        was one of the largest and most significant libraries of the ancient world.\n
        It was dedicated to the Muses, the nine goddesses of the arts.\n
        It flourished under the patronage of the Ptolemaic dynasty and functioned as a major center of scholarship from
        its construction in the 3rd century BC until the Roman conquest of Egypt in 30 BC, with collections of works,
        lecture halls, meeting rooms, and gardens.\n Alexandria was considered the capital of knowledge and learning,
        in part because of the Great Library. \nThe library was part of a larger research institution called the Musaeum of Alexandria,
        where many of the most famous thinkers of the ancient world studied.\n
        The library was created by Ptolemy I Soter, who was a Macedonian general and the successor of Alexander the Great.\n
        Most of the books were kept as papyrus scrolls. \nIt is unknown precisely how many such scrolls were housed at any given time,
        but estimates range from 40,000 to 400,000 at its height.\n
        Arguably, this library is most famous for having been burned down resulting in the loss of many scrolls and books;
        its destruction has become a symbol for the loss of cultural knowledge.\n
        Sources differ on who was responsible for its destruction and when it occurred.\n
        The library may in truth have suffered several fires over many years.\n
        In addition to fires, at least one earthquake damaged the city and the library during this time.\n
        Possible occasions for the partial or complete destruction of the Library of Alexandria include a fire set
        by the army of Julius Caesar in 48 BC and an attack by Aurelian in the 270s AD.\n
        After the main library was destroyed, scholars used a "daughter library" in a temple known as the Serapeum of Alexandria,
        located in another part of the city. \nAccording to Socrates of Constantinople,
        Coptic Pope Theophilus destroyed the Serapeum in AD 391,
        although it is not certain what it contained or if it contained any significant fraction of the documents
        that were in the main library.
    </string>
    <string name="graeco_roman_museum">
        The Graeco-Roman Museum is an archaeological museum located in Alexandria, Egypt.\n
        Erected in 1892, it was first built in a five-room apartment,
        inside one small building on Rosetta Street (later Avenue Canope and now Horriya).\n
        In 1895, it was transferred to another, larger building near Gamal Abdul Nasser Street.\n
        The museum contains several pieces dating from the Graeco-Roman (Ptolemaic) era in the 3rd century BC,
        such as a sculpture of Apis in black granite, the sacred bull of the Egyptians, mummies, sarcophagus, tapestries,
        and other objects offering a view of Greco-Roman civilization in contact with ancient Egypt.\n
        The museum\'s collection is the product of donations from wealthy Alexandrians as well as of excavations led
        by successive directors of the institution, both within the town and in its environs.\n
        Certain other objects have come from the Organization of Antiquities at Cairo (particularly those of the Pharaonic period)
        and from various digs undertaken at the beginning of the century in Fayoum and at Benhasa.\n
        Housed within a historic building whose beautiful neoclassical facade of six columns and pediment
        bears the large Greek inscription ‘MOYΣEION’ (MOUSEION).\n
        The museum consists of 27 halls and an attractive garden,
        which offer an excellent introduction to Egypt\'s Greco-Roman period.
    </string>
    <string name="montaza_palace">
        The extensive Montaza Palace grounds first had the Salamlek Palace, built in 1892 by Khedive Abbas II,
        the last Muhammad Ali Dynastyruler to hold the Khedive title over the Khedivate of Egypt and Sudan.\n
        It was used as a hunting lodge and residence for his companion.\n
        The larger Al-Haramlik Palace and royal gardens were added to the Montaza Palace grounds, being built by King Fuad I in 1932,
        as a summer palace. \nIt is in a mixture of Ottoman and Florentine styles, with two towers.\n
        One of these towers rises distinctively high above with elaborated Italian Renaissance design details.\n
        The palace has long open arcades facing the sea along each floor.\n
        President Anwar El-Sadat renovated the original Salamlek Palace as an official presidential residence.
    </string>
    <string name="opera_house">
       Alexandria Opera House Constructed in 1918 during the reign of Sultan Fuad 1.\n
        It named Muhammad Ali Theater.\n The original owner of Alexandria of it.\n In 1921,
        Alexandria Opera House was host to celebrated Arab and foreign singers.\n
        In 1962 Alexandria Opera House renamed “Sayed Darwish Theater” to honor Mr.Sayed Darwish.\n
        Sayd Darwish a famous Egyptian musician.\n Moreover, Sayd Darwish is the one who composed the Egyptian national anthem.\n
        Unfortunately, the ravages of time destroyed the exquisite beauty of Alexandria Opera House Building.
    </string>
    <string name="san_stefano">
        San Stefano Grand Plaza Alexandria is a structural complex.\n
        It includes Four Seasons Hotel, apartments, offices and a shopping mall.\n
        Moreover, it also has a marina in Alexandria, Egypt.\n Furthermore, it is on of its most luxurious areas in Alexandria.\n
        Four Seasons hotel features spacious gues rooms. Rooms feature balconies with view of the city, pool, or sea.\n
        They also feature LED TVs, signature bedding and marble bathrooms.\n The bathrooms are with deep soaking tubs.
    </string>
    <string name="city_centre">
        Suitably located on the Alexandria Cairo Desert Road, opposite to the Alexandria International Park,
        City Centre Alexandria is just 15 minutes from downtown.\n
        The landmark shopping destination opened in January 2003 to offer its customers a unique shopping and entertainment experience.\n
        The Centre has recently completed a massive extension programme that has increased the total number of retail stores in the mall
        from 97 to over 160, spread over a trading area of 60,370 square metres.\n
        With an eclectic mix of world class brands and retailers, a 14,771 square metre Carrefour Hypermarket, seven-screen renaissance cinema,
        an international food court and the popular family entertainment destination- Magic Planet- City Centre Alexandria
        is the biggest shopping mall in the city.\n
        It provides an international shopping experience to the residents and visitors of Alexandria.
    </string>
    <string name="northern_coast">
        On contrast to Egypt\'s Red Sea Riviera,
        its Mediterranean coastline is totally plain with low altitude shrublands along the region,
        except for the westernmost portion which is formed by the 400m-high Marmarika Plateau.\n
        It is also characterised by the occurrence of Egypt\'s five northernmost lakes.\n
        The region has typical Mediterranean flora and fauna on land and in marine life with the weather being between pleasant and hot
        during summer and mild in winter. \nThe region receives the most rain in Egypt, hail and sleet fall rarely in winter.\n
        Snowfallsoccur in some inland towns and locations.
    </string>
    <string name="greek_era">
        331 BCE – Rhacotis renamed "Alexandria" by Alexander the Great (approximate date).\n
        330 BCE – Cleomenes of Naucratis appointed Governor of Egypt by Alexander, begins to turn the small village into the Capitol of Egypt.\n
        323–30 BCE Egypt\'s capital under Ptolemaic dynasty
        323 BCE – Alexander dies.\n Ptolemy I Soter appointed "Satrap" of Egypt.\n
        305 BCE – Ptolemy I proclaims himself king.\n
        283 BCE – Library of Alexandria opens (approximate date).\n
        247 BCE – Lighthouse of Alexandria built (approximate date).\n
        170 BCE – Selucid "Emperor" Antiochus IV Epiphanes briefly conquers Egypt
        168 BCE – First Roman intervention.\n City briefly invaded.\n
        1st century BC – Caesareum built.\n
        50 BC–330 CE Romans in power\n
        48 BCE – Julius Caesar conquers Alexandria.\n
        48 BCE – Great Royal Library of Alexandria burned.\n
        47 BCE – Siege of Alexandria.\n
        47 BCE – Caesar victorious.\n
        44 BCE – Assassination of Julius Caesar in Rome.\n
        40 BCE – Cleopatra VII marries Roman triumvir Mark Antony.\n
        31 BCE – Death of Antony and Cleopatra.\n
        30 BCE – Battle of Alexandria.\n
        29 BCE – Augustus takes city.\n Cornelius Gallus first prefect of Egypt.\n
        25 BCE – Strabo, the Greek geographer and philosopher, visits Alexandria.\n
        19 CE – Germanicus resident in city.\n
        38 CE – Pogrom against Jews.\n
        115 CE – City sacked during a Jewish revolt.\n Possible genocide.\n
        122 CE – Hadrian rebuilds city.\n
        175 CE – Failed revolution of Avidius Cassius.\n
        176 CE – Catechetical School of Alexandria (oldest such school in the world) founded.\n Some records say 190 AD. \nSee article.\n
        297 CE – Pompey\'s Pillar built.\n
        365 CE – The 365 Crete earthquake affects the Greek island of Crete with a maximum Mercalli intensity of XI (Extreme),
        causing a destructive tsunami that affects the coasts of Libya and Egypt, especially Alexandria.\n Many thousands were killed.
    </string>
    <string name="rules">
        Byzantine rule 390–650\n
       \n 391 CE – Theodosius I orders destruction of pagan temples.\n
        395 CE – Roman Empire formally split in two.\n The official start of so-called Byzantine Empire.\n
        415 CE – Lynching of the philosopher Hypatia by a radical Christian mob. \n
        The expulsion of the Jews from Alexandria, in 414 or 415 CE under the leadership of Saint Cyril.\n
        Around 100000 Jews expelled - another Pogrom or "Alexandria Expulsion".\n
        619 CE – City besieged; Sassanid Persians in power.\n
        641–642 CE – City besieged; Arabs in power; capital of Egypt relocates from Alexandria to Fustat.\n
        645 CE – Byzantines back in power.\n
      \n  Muslim Rule 700–1800\n
        \n680 CE – Saint Mark\'s Coptic Orthodox Cathedral rebuilt.\n
        956 CE – Earthquake.\n
        1303 CE – Earthquake.\n
        1323 CE – Earthquake.\n The Pharos lighthouse collapses.\n
        1354 CE – Eliyahu Hanavi Synagogue built.\n
        1365 CE – October: City besieged by Cypriot forces.\n
        1381 CE – Zaradel Synagogue established.\n
        1477 CE – Citadel of Qaitbay established.\n
        1519 CE – Ottoman conquest\n
        1775 – El-Mursi Abul Abbas Mosque built.\n
        1798 – French forces under Napoleon Bonaparte besiege and conquer what is now just a town.\n
        1800 – Nadir of the city.\n Population: a mere 8,000.\n
    </string>
    <string name="the_19th_century">
        1801\n
        21 March: Battle between French and British forces.\n
        17 August – 2 September: City besieged by British forces.\n
        2 September: Capitulation to British.\n
        1819 – Mahmoudiyah Canal constructed.\n
        1821 – Population: 12,528.\n
        1829 – Dockyard and arsenal open.\n
        1833 – April: Luxor Obelisk shipped to Paris.\n
        1834 – Ras el-Tin Palace construction begins.\n
        1840 – Population: 60,000.\n
        1847 – Ras el-Tin Palace built.\n
        1850 – Eliyahu Hanavi Synagogue restored.\n
        1853 – Azouz Synagogue rebuilt.\n
        1856\n
        Cairo-Alexandria railway begins operating.\n
        Cathedral of Evangelismos dedicated.\n
        1859\n
        Institut d\'Egypte founded.\n
        Theatre Europeen reopens.\n
        1860 – Alexandria Ramleh Train Station established.\n
        1862 – Theatre Zizinia built.\n
        1861 – Cotton boom.\n
        1863\n
        Horse-drawn trams begin operating.\n
        Population: 170,000.\n
        1865 – Gas lighting introduced.\n
        1865–1869 – New port created.\n
        1872 – Population ca.\n 200,000 (ca. 20% foreigners).\n
        1873\n
        Breakwater built in harbor.\n
        Statue unveiled in Midan Muhammad Ali.\n
        1875 – Al-Ahram newspaper begins publication.\n
        1877 – One of Cleopatra\'s Needles shipped to London.\n
        1880 – The Egyptian Gazette launched in Alexandria.\n
        1880 – One of Cleopatra\'s Needles shipped to New York City.\n
        1880 – Zaradel Synagogue restored.\n
        1881 – al-Tankit wa al-Tabkit newspaper begins publication.\n
        1882\n
        11 July: Anti-European riots; city bombarded by British naval forces.\n
        Population: 232,626.\n
        1883 – Alexandria Stock Exchange founded.\n
        1887 – El-Hakaneia Palace built.\n
        1892\n
        Graeco-Roman Museum established.\n
        Salamlek Palace built.
    </string>
    <string name="the_20th_century">
        1901 – Green Synagogue established.\n
        1902\n
        Electric trams begin operating.\n
        Victoria College founded.\n
        1903 – Khedivial yacht club built.\n
        1905 – Sea wall constructed.\n
        1907 – Population: 332,246.\n
        1910 – Hellenic Football Club Alexandria formed.\n
        1910 – Sasson Synagogue established.\n
        1914 – Al Ittihad Alexandria Club formed.\n
        1917 – Population ca. \n460,000 (ca. 20% foreigners).\n
        1919 – Princess Fatma Al-Zahra palace built.\n
        1920 – Castro Synagogue established.\n
        1920 – Nezah Israel Synagogue established.\n
        1921 – Alexandria Opera House opens.\n
        1922 – Shaaré Tefila Synagogue established.\n
        1925 – Scottish School for Girls founded.\n
        1927 – Population ca.\n 600,000 (ca. 17% foreigners).\n
        1928 – Collège Saint Marc founded.\n
        1929\n
        Alexandria Stadium opens.\n
        English Boys\' School established.\n
        1930 – Alexandria Aquarium opens.\n
        1932 – Al-Haramlik Palace built.\n
        1934 – Corniche constructed.\n
        1935 – English Girls College founded.\n
        1937 – Eliahou Hazan Synagogue established.\n
        1938 – Publication of The Egyptian Gazette moved from Alexandria to Cairo.\n
        1941 – 19 December: Conflict between Italian and British naval forces.\n
        1942 – Farouk University established.\n
        1947 – Population: 919,024; (ca. 7% foreigners).\n
        1950 – Hassab hospital established.\n
        1952 – Egyptian Revolution.\n
        1954 – 26 October: Attempted assassination of Nasser during speech in Mansheya.\n
        1958 – Alexandria Zoo opens.\n
        1960 – Siddiq Abdul-Latif becomes mayor.\n
        1964 – September: Arab League summit held.\n
        1965 – Population ca. 1.5 million.\n
        1969 – St. Takla Haymanot\'s Church consecrated.\n
        1974 – Population: 2,259,000.\n
        1980 – El Alamein-Alexandria highway constructed.\n
        1986\n
        Ismail El-Gawsaqi becomes mayor.\n
        Port of Dekheila constructed.\n
        Royal Jewelry Museum inaugurated.\n
        1990 – Senghor University founded.\n
        1992 – Population: 3,380,000 (estimate).\n
        1996 – Alexandria Institute Of Technology founded.\n
        1997 – Abdel-Salam El-Mahgoub becomes mayor.\n
        1999 – Swedish Institute Alexandria established.\n
    </string>


    <string name="Fragment1">Geo</string>
    <string name="Fragment2">Historical</string>
    <string name="Fragment3">Public</string>
    <string name="Fragment4">Entertainment</string>
    <string name="Fragment5">Events</string>
    <string name="Fragment6">Secrets</string>
    <string name="title">Title</string>
    <string name="data">Data</string>
    <string name="details">Details</string>
</resources>
